Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
Cornell University, New York State College of Home Economics records,
- Series V. Student Activities
  - College of Home Economics--Dean's Office
    - Vocational interest forms for students (Box 83)
- Series VI. Teaching and Research
  - Child Development, Family Relations
    - The Causes and Treatment of Enuresis in the Pre-School Child 1926. An exploratory study of the relationships between the parental control and acceptance of rural children and the behavior and attitudes of the children toward their younger siblings Purnell #360 CDFR; Development of Thinking in Children, State Project #25 CDFR, 1925-1957 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Some aspects of Cognitive Development during Infancy and the Pre-school Years. State #32 CDFR, 1958-1960 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Sociological Studies of the Family, State #34 CDFR; Adult Influence and Child Behavior, State #35 CDFR; Explorations of Conceptions Expressed in Play, Fantasies and Dreams, State #41 CDFR; Family Factors in the Development of Entrepreneurial Ability, State #42 CDFR, 1958=1960 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Personality Factors Associated with Role Gratification in Women, State #20 Grant; Pride and Shame in Children, State #21 (CDFR) Grant; Effects upon Creativity and Family Interaction of Participation in a Creative Expression Program; State #22 (CDFR:l Grant, 1956-1960 (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - A Study-of the Practices and Values of Rural Families in Rearing Pre-school Childres Purnell #355 CDFR, 1947-1952 (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - A Study of patterns of control and acceptance in the child rearing practices of 91 rural mothers, Purnell #369 CDFR, 1949-1955 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Changing structure of the rural community with implications for rural programming, Purnell #389 CDFR; Family Structure and Personality Development, State #31 Grant CDFR; How Children Learn to Read, State #33 Grant CDFR, 1955-1960 (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Cornell Studies in Social Growth: a) Springdale Project, b) Identification of Family Structure, State #3 CDFR includes progress reports, project statements, grant foundation assistantships, correspondence, U.S. Public Health Service, and Markle Foundation, 1948-1958 (Box 21, Folder 52-62)
  - Home Economics Education
    - Factors in School and Community Situations that are related to Effectiveness of High School Home Economics Programs (Home Economics Education) State #9, 1950-1960 (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - Contributions of the High School Home Economics Program toward improved family living in the community (Home Ec. Ed.) State #13, 1954-1959 (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - Study of Community Approach to Student Teaching (Home Economics Education) U State #15; Factors Related to the Selection of College Teachers in Home Economics (Home Economics Education) State #28; Measurement of Values of Home Economics Teachers, (Home Economics Education) State #37; Evaluation of Senior High School Courses in Family Relationships, (Home Economics Education) State #36 Grant, 1955-1960 (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - Cornell Refresher Conference for Teachers -"Work Conference on Life Adjustment Education", 1948 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Jr. High School Homemaking Curriculum Workshop for Homemaking Teachers at Buffalo, New York, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - An Overview of the Workshop in Curriculum Planning for Early Secondary Education in Homemaking at Cornell, 1956 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Workshop and Field Experiences in Home Economics in Home Economics Education - Ethelwyn Cornelius and Marjorie Swift - Cornell University, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Field Experience in Home Economics Education - Summer Visit Reports - Ethelwyn Cornelius, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Field Experience in Home Economics Education -Summer Visit Reports - Marjorie Swift, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Overview of the Workshop in Secondary Education (with Focus on Homemaking 3) Summer Session at Cornell, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Pre-planning for the Workshop, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence concerning the Refresher Conference, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Summer Session at Cornell, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Workshop in Curriculum Planning for Early Secondary Education in Homemaking, Summer Session at Cornell, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - New York State Conference for Homemaking Teachers -Registration Packet, 1953 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - New York State Conference for Homemaking Teachers, Resource Center, Rooms, Study Groups, Evaluation, 1953 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Conference - Publicity - Source of Audio Visual Material and the Conference Program Folder Description, 1953 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Committee on Home Economics in Higher Education - Report -Chicago, Illinois, 1951 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Workshop on Family Life Education - Margaret Hutchins,Coordinator - Summer Session at Cornell, 1951 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Refresher Conference - Program and Registrants and material from the program - Summer Session at Cornell, 1950 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Refresher Conferences for Home Economics Teachers at Cornell, 1946-1949 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - College Faculty Workshop -Albany, New York, 1942 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - New York State Conference for Homemaking Teachers - Syracuse, 1941 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Bulletin Boards done by Home Economics Students in Trumansburg, 1964 (Box 87, Folder 21)
  - Textiles and Clothing
    - Textile Investigation, 1923-1924 (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - Study of clothing of pre-school children as it relates to their behavior and development, Purnell #350 TC and CDFR, 1946-1950 (Box 21, Folder 67)
    - Selection, Care and Management of Household Textiles, 1929-1930, Purnell TC; TC A study of performance during wear of women's and children's silk, rayon, and cotton wearing apparel fabrics, Purnell #310 TC; Consumer satisfaction with Garments as Related to characteristics of the Garments and consumer practices in selection, use, and care, Hatch Amended #159, 1929-1960 (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - Psychology of Clothing, State #4 TC; Serviceability and care of selected materials containing Nylon, Dacron, and Acrylic Fibers, State #12 TC; Laboratory performance of new winter cottons and blends or mixtures in cleaning or laundering processes and in laundering or cleaning alternated with abrasives, State #14 TC; Comparative warmth of Blankets, State #29 TC; motivation and Satisfaction in the Selection and Use of Clothing Items, State #30 TC, 1949-1960 (Box 21, Folder 69)
  - Housing and Design
    - Space, Facility and Structural Regulations for Farm Houses in the Northeast Region, Research and Marketing #3, N.E. #7 H D, 1977-1954 (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - Determination of Housing Needs and Preferences of Families Engaged in Each Major Type of Farming in New York State, R and M #3 H and D, 1947-1949 (Box 21, Folder 71-72)
    - Study of Housing Requirement and House Improvement Practices of Rural Families in five Selected Areas of New York State, R and M #17 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Criteria for Improved Housing Design based on family living characteristics, State #10, Hatch #112, R and M #42 H and D; Basic Space Requirements in N.E. Farm Houses as Influenced by Activity Patterns, R and M #62 H and D;R and M Housing Needs of the Aged in Urban and Rural Areas, Hatch Amended #203 H and D; The Measurement of rural housing quality, Hatch Amended #204 H and D (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Criteria for design and planning of bathrooms, Hatch #252 H and D; Farm House Storage Facilities for food Commodities and Related Equipment, State #8 H and D; Home Buying and Financing Trends in Selected Urban Areas of New York State, State #28 H and D; Research in Residential Lighting, State #18 H and D; Grant; Housing Values, State #19 H and D; Grant (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - includes reports, N.E.#7, R and M #3 (Box 22, Folder 4-8)
    - State Rural Housing Research (Grace Marin and others) (Box 22, Folder 9-13)
  - Food and Nutrition
    - Department of Nutrition Studies; state and federal projects (Box 22, Folder 14-31)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1957 (Box 22, Folder 32-36)
    - Course Syllabi and Exams for Mary Henry's Courses, 1929-1931 (Box 22, Folder 58)
  - Household Management
    - Department of Household Management Studies; state and federal projects (Box 22, Folder 37-49)
    - Development of functional basis for kitchen designing (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Miss Sowers' Research on Practice House, 1931 (Box 22, Folder 51-53)
  - Institutional Management
    - Department of Institutional Management Studies; state and federal projects (Box 22, Folder 54-57)
  - Hotel Administration
    - Stoves and ranges project, 1924 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous projects (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Projects never initiated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports
    - 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 1945-1955 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - 1937-1940 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - 1932-1934 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - 1930-1932 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - 1926-1930 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - College of Home Economics Finance Research, 1922-1924 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Annual Reports on Research, 1949-1959 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Research in Progress, 1922-1960 (Box 23, Folder 25-28)
  - Miscellaneous Reports
    - 1923-1926 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Memos, reports, 1923-1930 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Faculty Studies in Home Economics, 1924-1929 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Report on Vital Research, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Research problems in Household Economy, 1925-1926 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Home Economics Research and Research Questionnaire, 1927, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Research in Foods and Nutrition Standards, 1929-1930 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Cost of Living Research Program, 1930-1940 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Study of school lunchroom work in some New York State schools and form for reporting projects, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Bills before Congress, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Research projects - Cornell Experiment Station, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Research projects - Memos and Research Agreements, 1941-1946 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Medical Advisory Committee on Food and Nutrition Research and miscellaneous research materials, 1946-1949 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Statement of Policy concerning research contracts; theses in Home Economics; statement of patent policy; trends in Home Economics research., 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Calendar of scheduled meetings and administrative dates, 1950-1967 (Box 23, Folder 38-40)
    - Financing of research projects, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Memos and reports, 1953-1957 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Contributions of research program to graduate programs, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Home Economics at university level, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - The Forward Look in Home Economics Research, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Report to Visiting Committee on Biological Science, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 44-45)
    - Textiles and Clothing Research (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - History of Research and College Research Committee
    - College Committee on Research to Dean Canoyer, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Research policies and practices, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - Research Policy and Practice, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 48)
      Revised
    - Statement of research policy and practice, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Report of College Research Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Statement of research policy, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Report of College Research Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - Report of College Research Committee, 1949-1952 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - Report of College Research Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - Activities and discussions of the research committee, 1947-1955 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - College Research Committee, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Committee on Research and Graduate Study, 1932-1934 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - History of the Research Committee, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Historical review of research, 1925-1937 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Research - committee meetings, 1950-1957 (Box 23, Folder 52-57)
    - Director of Research - correspondence, 1922-1931 (Box 23, Folder 56-58)
    - Coordinator of Research in Home Economics (Catherine J. Personius) (Box 23, Folder 59)
  - Research Studies
    - Posture studies, 1930-1939 (Box 84)
    - Contains samples household work surveys done in Baldwin, New York for the College of Home Economics, 1964 (Box 89)
  - Farm Homemakers Use of Time - Thirteen volumes Genesee County, 1936
    - Batavia No. 11-114 (Volume 1)
    - Batavia No. 115-187 (Volume 2)
    - Batavia No. 190-303 (Volume 3)
    - Bergen No. 3-76 (Volume 4)
    - Bergen No. 78-171 (Volume 5)
    - Bethany No. 4-90 (Volume 6)
    - Bethany No. 95-175 (Volume 7)
    - Byron (Volume 8)
    - Pavilion No. 2-93 (Volume 9)
    - Pavilion No. 94-181 (Volume 10)
    - Stafford No. 1-108 (Volume 11)
    - Stafford No. 111-196 (Volume 12)
    - Seasonal Records from all Townships (Volume 13)
- Series VII. Extension
  - General Information
    - Early history of extension, 1915-1956 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Extension correspondence(including potato patriotism folder 6), 1907-1921 (Box 24, Folder 2-10)
    - Extension policy, 1919-1945 (Box 24, Folder 11-12)
    - Extension schools, including 1908 program from the School of Graduate Workers in Home Economics held at Cornell, 1908-1927 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Extension staff - voting privilege, 1925 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Junior Extension, 1914-1926 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Extension expense accounts - some early examples, 1914-1915 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Extension teaching preparation for careers in extension, 1920-1927 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Extension services in other states - correspondence, 1907-1918 (Box 24, Folder 18-19)
    - Preparation of extension publications, 1905-1920 (Box 24, Folder 20-21)
    - Distribution, use of, and quotation from extension publications, 1906-1921 (Box 24, Folder 22-25)
    - Extension Publications Committee, 1916-1917 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - New York State Extension Federation of 4-H Clubs, 1932-1945 (Box 24, Folder 27-28)
    - Extension materials, 1912-1934 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Farmers' Wives Reading Course and Clubs
    - Early history, 1900-1914 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1905-1921 (Box 24, Folder 31-43)
    - Reading Course for Farm Home and Cornell Study Clubs; clippings and correspondence, 1901-1939 (Box 24, Folder 44-47)
    - Farmers' Wives Reading Course and Clubs - testimonials, 1916-1923 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Reading Course - letters from readers, 1903-1923 (Box 24, Folder 49-53)
    - Envelopes - post cards from readers, 1906-1921 (Box 24, Folder 54-64)
    - Envelopes - post cards from readers, 1906-1921 (Box 25, Folder 1-8)
    - Reading Course testimonials on large index cards, 1901-1940 (Box 25, Folder 9-16)
    - Reading Course for the Farm Home Reports, 1903-1917 (Box 25, Folder 17-20)
    - Problems of Extension Organization, 1915-1925 (Box 25, Folder 21-24)
    - Cornell Study Clubs - Programs (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Study Clubs and Home Bureau: Rise of Home Bureau, Decline of Study Clubs, 1918-1922 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Use of Other Communications Media
    - Early Radio Work, 1925-1930 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - State College Radio Committee, 1930-1941 (Box 25, Folder 28-29)
    - Federal Movie of New York State College of Home Economics, 1946-1950 (Box 25, Folder 30-35)
    - Cooperation in state and county fairs, 1906-1913 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Publicists and advertisers, correspondence, 1917-1920 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Worlds Fair Exhibit, 1937-1940 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Cooperative Extension work in Colleges of Agriculture and Home Economics, "Better Living on the Farm", 1941-1943 (Box 25, Folder 39-40)
    - "Victory Special" Train, correspondence, 1912-1920 (Box 25, Folder 41)
- Series VIII. Correspondence
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and R. H. Wheeler, Extension Professor, 1914-1924 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and M. C. Burritt, Vice-Director of Extension, 1915-1920 (Box 25, Folder 43-48)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with A. R. Mann, 1908-1929 (Box 25, Folder 49-58)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with A. R. Mann, 1922-1931 (Box 25, Folder 59-60)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with L. H. Bailey, 1906-1922 (Box 25, Folder 61-64)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with W. A. Stocking, 1913-1920 (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with Charles Tuck, 1907-1915 (Box 25, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with George A. Works, 1915-1918 (Box 25, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence:Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with Cornelius Betten, 1917-1932 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with President Schurman, 1908-1919 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with Agriculture professors, 1908-1921 (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
  - Correspondence: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose with non-Agriculture faculty, 1911-1920 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with the Hoovers, 1917-1931 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Franklin Roosevelt, 1928-1937 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with the Roosevelts, 1924 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Eleanor Roosevelt, 1925-1941 (Box 26, Folder 11-23)
  - Correspondence with prominent figures, 1905-1936 (Box 26, Folder 24-25)
  - Invitations and calling cards, 1932-1938 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (including correspondence about the death of Helen Canon; and correspondence concerning Belgium Medals of Honor-actual medals in boxes 111 and 112 (museum collection #'s 330-338), 1901-1954 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Photocopies of correspondence from the Franklin D. Roosevelt Library -to/from Martha Van Rensselaer and Franklin Roosevelt and to/from Louise Stanley and the Hoovers, 1919-1947 (Box 110, Folder 1-2)
  - Photocopies of Eleanor Roosevelt's column "My Day" with references to Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose, 1926-1947 (Box 110, Folder 1-2)
  - Additional Correspondence
    - Martha Van Rensselaer, 1916-1931 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer, 1921 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Helen Canon, 1919-1946 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - MVR and Flora Rose with Mary Henry, 1918-1921 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Flora Rose, 1910-1928 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Flora Rose, 1929-1938 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Flora Rose, 1940-1941 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Flora Rose, 1941-1947 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Flora Rose and interview with Flora Rose, 1950-1959 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence from Alumni Concerning the Appointment of a Woman Dean, 1931 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence concerning two Native American Students in the College of Home Economics, 1931 (Box 59)
    - Women's Positions, 1944, 1947, 1962 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Helen Canoyer-Correspondence and Speeches, 1956-1964 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Admissions Folder for a Student not Accepted, 1939 (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - Exhibition Catalog from Costume Exhibition in the College, by Elsie Frost, 1928 (Box 102, Folder 14)
- Series IX. Furnishings
  - Orders for Entire Building - Department of Home Economics, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
  - Acoustics; contains printed material, 1931-1933 (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
  - Miscellaneous - includes fabric samples (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Estimates, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Kitchens - blueprint and printed material, 1930-1931 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Labs - Psychological, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Cafeteria Lobby - includes sketches, 1915-1918 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Room G/71 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Furniture - miscellaneous extras, 1933-1938 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Building equipment - Doris Schumaker; Miss Brucher, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Requisitions - New Building, 1929-1930 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Household Art Design and Crafts Lab (Box 27, Folder 15)
    Includes photographs and fabric samples
  - Household Art equipment - old; with sketches, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Household Art storage - general (information about companies manufacturing building supplies), 1928-1929 (Box 27, Folder 17-18)
  - Labs - Clothing; Stenographic Room; Girl's Lounge; Exhibition Rooms; Class Rooms; Conference Rooms, Canon Reading; Labs. Food and Nutrition, 1929-1934 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Recreation Room (pending) - with blueprints, sketches, fabric samples, 1934-1935 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Design and crafts lab.; storage; draperies; Household Art color and Design Lab; Household Art office, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Supplies; House Planning and Furnishing Lab; Housemaking Apartments, 1933-1946 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Building Equipment
    - 1932-1933 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Census data, 1946-1947 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Lines - Tables, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - House Planning Flats; Grad Lounge; Freshman Reading Room; Waiting Room Costume Shop, 1933-1935 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Corridor lockers (recessed); closets; furnishings, 1930-1933 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Room G/71; Household Art Extension Work Room, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Supplies; Crafts laboratory (no equipment); Household Art office; Miss Blackmore's office - color and design lab, 1935-01 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Office - Erway and Scott; Miss Marin's office,Room 401 - loft, 1935-01 (Box 27, Folder 30-31)
    - Acoustics, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 32-33)
    - Floor treatments; printed materials, 1921-1932 (Box 27, Folder 34-38)
    - Dryer; tracings of equipment; F and N; measurements; preliminary plans; other buildings - includes blueprints and sketches (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Reading Room includes blueprints, fabric samples, 1932-1933 (Box 27, Folder 40-42)
    - Equipment - other buildings, 1930-1933 (Box 27, Folder 43-44)
    - Room 325 Household Art Department; New Building - financial; partitions; 404 Faculty Lounge, 1931-1938 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Walls, curtains for offices; Empire Case Goods, 1931-1933 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Waiting room; Faculty Lounge pending; Library; departmental equipment; apartments (current); apartments - nursery; Household Art Department miscellaneous equipment, 1930-1934 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Apartment - 1st floor; paint; plumbing, 1933-1935 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - New Building - blueprint requests; second-hand furniture; measurements, partition; Constant Temperature Room; telephones.71, 1929-1933 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Walls, curtains for offices; Empire Case Goods, 1934 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Furniture orders, furniture received; furnishings, miscellaneous, hardware; plans, 1930-1931 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - Pianos - victrolas; general storage; vacuum cleaners; ventilation; tables; telephones; committee - equipment; directory board - photographs, 1928-1933 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - Shades - printed material, 1930-1932 (Box 27, Folder 52-53)
    - Syren Mocey Company - filing systems - include blueprints and sketches, 1931-1933 (Box 27, Folder 54-55)
    - Apartment B (Box 27, Folder 56-57)
    - Correspondence - New Building, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 58)